# Calvin Chun-Yu Chan

Senior Software Engineer

hello@calvincchan.com Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada Web: <u>calvincchan.com</u>
Github: <u>github.com/calvincchan</u>
Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/in/calvincchan</u>



### **INTRO**

My startup journey has taught me to build quickly, learn from mistakes, and embrace change based on feedback and validation. I have designed the architecture of numerous systems, built API servers, developed web and mobile clients, managed cloud infrastructure and container orchestration using Docker, and implemented automated deployment pipelines. I believe AI is the future and am passionate about applying it to products to drive innovation, enhance user experiences, and improve productivity.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Founding Software Engineer - EDU.INK Limited (Hong Kong)

Jun 2019 - Present

#### **Impacts**

- Led the development of a real-time collaborative CMS application using React and Supabase to modernize secure information sharing among leadership, nurses, and other contributors of the school learning support team.
- Led the development of all major products, including a student information system, admission and enrolment system, billing and online payment system, library system, school bus tracking system, and parent-teacher communication platform.
- Led the transition from the legacy monolithic PHP Laravel app to a client-server architecture with Node.js + MongoDB backend, Vue.js frontend, and React Native mobile apps. This resulted in dramatic improvements in service responsiveness, development speed, and maintainability.

#### Responsibilities

- Collaborate with clients and business team to elicit requirements and design prototypes.
- Researched and evaluated new tech stacks and applied them to product developments.
- Design and implement micro-services and clients quickly to iterate based on feedbacks.
- Coordinate with 2 React Native developers to manage the iOS/Android mobile app development, testing, deployment and release pipelines on both platforms.

#### **Technology**

 Node.js, Javascript/Typescript, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Jest, Supabase, Docker, Fastify, Restify, Express.js, OpenAPI, Stripe, Active Directory, OneSignal, Vue.js (v2), React.js, Material UI, refine.js, React Native, CircleCI, BitBucket Pipeline, AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, Docker, AWS S3, Google Cloud Platform, Axure RP, Adobe Illustrator

# Founding Software Engineer - GUZZU Limited (Shenzhen, China)

Jun 2016 - Sep 2019

#### **Impacts**

- Implemented an expat-focused e-commerce platform featuring a bilingual interface to help English-speaking business owners manage their businesses and serve Chinese customers.
- Built WeChat mini-programs that allow merchants to engage easily with local customers.
- Collaborated with an Android developer to create a proof-of-concept merchant POS terminal.
- Streamlined local event hosting by custom-building a mobile-web event ticket sales platform, including a management backend and a barcode scanning ticket validation app.

## Responsibilities

- Directed a team of 2 developers in developing the Node.js API servers, mobile web clients and WeChat mini programs for multiple e-commerce products including: an inventory management system, shopping apps for mobile web, WeChat integration, online payment gateway integration, customizable storefronts, and e-ticket issuance and redemption system.
- Engaged with local expat merchants to strategize new products and features.

## **Technology**

· Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Redis, Vue.js, WeChat Mini Program SDK, Aliyun Cloud

## **Contract Software Engineer - archiparti.co (Hong Kong)**

Apr 2015 - Apr 2016

 Built software solutions for architects to simplify the management of their interior design projects, enabling them to focus on their creative process rather than organizing documents and paperwork.

## **Technology**

Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Angular.js, AWS

# Founding Software Engineer - giftpass.cn (Shanghai, China)

Mar 2013 - Jun 2015

- As a team in the Chinaccelerator incubator program, I designed and implemented a digital gift voucher platform that streamlines the management and consumption lifecycle for both consumers and merchants.
- Created a merchant app for managing offers, scanning and redeeming gift vouchers.
- Designed pitch decks, visuals and prototypes.
- Rapidly built proof-of-concept projects and MVPs.

#### **Technology**

· Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Apple Wallet SDK, Angular.js, WeChat, Aliyun Cloud

# **UX Designer - Genesix Inc. (Japan)**

May 2011 - Jul 2012

- Worked with product managers and iOS engineers on the Jumvo app, a voice based instant messaging tool which received positive user feedbacks and sparked interests in the southeast asian market.
- Contributed to other mobile web marketing projects
- Designed the user experience, interface, and visual elements for iOS and mobile web apps.
- · Conducted user interviews and research.

#### **Technology**

· Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, jQuery Mobile

# Web Designer and Engineer - A.C.O. Inc. (Japan)

Sep 2010 - Mar 2011

- Contributed to building websites for international corporate clients using web design, rapid prototyping, and UI engineering skills with technologies such as Adobe Fireworks and jQuery.
- Developed a Facebook Page and social application for global marketing initiatives that successfully increased brand awareness and user engagement.

## **Technology**

Adobe Fireworks, Adobe Photoshop, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery

# InnateDB Software Developer - The University of British Columbia (Canada)

Mar 2007 - Jun 2010

- Designed and implemented the search engine frontend for researchers to easily submit queries and interact with the database content.
- Worked with DB admins and project managers to build the interactive search engine frontend.
- Implemented data visualization and report generation features.

#### **Technology**

· Javascript, CSS, jQuery, HTML, PHP, CakePHP

## **EDUCATION**

## University of British Columbia — B.Sc., Computer Science

Sep 2000 - May 2003

For more information about me and my recent activities, please visit my personal site: <a href="mailto:calvincchan.com">calvincchan.com</a>